uea.ac.uk 2016-06-29

# Legal Statements - UEA

## **UEA Privacy Statement**

### **General conditions**

The University of East Anglia recognises that personal privacy is an important issue, and our website practices are in compliance with all relevant UK legislation.

This privacy policy explains what information we gather when you visit the University of East Anglia's central web site, and explains how that information is used. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. You should check this page from time to time to check for any changes to this policy.

Currently users are not required to register or provide any personal information in order to use the main web site at the University of East Anglia. No personal data is stored by or captured through the site without users' prior knowledge and consent.

Where personal information is captured (e.g. through web forms for feedback, requests, etc.), the user will be informed as to what information is being captured and why. Any personal information that you provide to us will be used only for the purpose stated at the time we request it. We will not sell, license or trade your personal information to others. We do not provide your personal information to direct marketing companies or other such organisations.

This privacy policy does not cover the links within this site to other non-University sites nor the content of external internet sites.

### **What data is collected?**

#### **Log files**

In common with most web sites, this site automatically logs certain information about every request made of it. The University's website does not automatically capture or store personal data from visitors to the site, other than to log your IP address and session information. Session information includes the time and duration of your visit to the site, the files requested, and the browser used.

This information will only be accessed by authorised persons of the University of East Anglia or its agents. The information will be retained by the University and will only be used for the purpose of (a) managing the site system, (b) the identification of broken links, (c) bug tracking and (d) for statistical and audit purposes.

Relevant subsets of this data may be passed to computer security teams as part of investigations of computer misuse involving this site or other computing equipment in the University. Data may be passed to the administrators of other computer systems to enable investigation of problems accessing this site or of system misconfigurations. Data may incidentally be included in information passed to contractors and computer maintenance organisations working for the University, in which case it will be covered by appropriate non-disclosure agreements.

#### **Personal data in forms**

A number of fill-in forms are provided on this site. The pages containing these forms include information on how data submitted on them will be processed and used, and such information is held by the University in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998. The information collected will only be used for the stated purpose, and, by supplying such information you consent to the University storing the information for that purpose.

## **Cookies**

When you visit the Website, the University may send your computer a "cookie", a small file that resides on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are text files, which identify a user's computer to our server but in no way gives the University access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share. Cookies are sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. Cookies in themselves identify the individual user, just the computer used. You can set your browser not to accept cookies, although you may not be able to access all of the features on the Website.

The University website uses cookies for collecting user information and allows the University to make the Website more useful by tailoring the services we offer from time to time. Some cookies are absolutely necessary for the website to work properly, some are used to improve the performance of the website, some are used to enhance the functionality based on the attributes and choices of the individual user, and some are used to offer products and services to the user based on their use of the site.

In line with changes in European legislation, UK law requires website operators to obtain the consent of the user for the placing of certain kinds of cookies on their devices for the first time. In particular, every cookie other than that necessary for the website to work requires consent and the UEA follows this practice. By using this website, you consent to the storing of the cookies listed here. This list identifies 4 types of cookies used:

Cookies | Description  
---|---  
Session | A session cookie is non-persistent, ie it only lasts for the duration of the user session/visit. The cookie is deleted at the end of the session by the browser. Example: cookie which identifies a user so that it can map them to their session state information found on the server.  
1st party | 1st party cookies are cookies set with the same domain (or subdomain) as the website. 1st party cookies are cookies that have been detected within the Header of the page. Example: sifa.uea.ac.uk which verifies the language being used by the visitor browser.  
3rd party | 3rd party cookies are cookies set with a different domain than that of the website. Example: twitter.com (to identify user between requests to the twitter website)  
Other | Other cookies are cookies that are set with the same domain as the website, but were not detected through the first check (i.e. in the Header). Therefore they could be cookies set by 3rd parties via JavaScript. Example: Google Analytics statistics cookies  
  
Implied consent can be inferred from continued use of a website where the user has been given sufficient information to understand that cookies are being used, and UEA has adopted this approach to consent.

You may refuse or control the use of cookies by changing the settings on your browser, choosing to allow them, block them, only allow them from selected sites or only allow certain types of cookies. Doing this, however, means you might not be able to access certain features of our site. For more information about cookies, please visit:

  * **General information** \- [AllAboutCookies website](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)
  * **Detailed information on the different kinds of cookies** \- [ICC UK Cookie Guide ](http://www.iccwbo.uk/pages/privacy)
  * **How to configure your browser to control cookie access** \- [UK ICO Cookie Advice](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-pecr/cookies-and-similar-technologies/) (NB just because browser software can block cookies, it does not mean that users who do not set their browsers to block cookies are effectively giving [consent to their use](http://www.jisclegal.ac.uk/ManageContent/ViewDetail/ID/2518/How-to-Manage-Cookies-Consent-Remains-Controversial.aspx)).

For your information, cookies employed by UEA include the use of Google Analytics and SiteImprove cookies to provide UEA management information, and other session management cookies to enhance user functionality. These are used on virtually all official UEA web pages. The University of East Anglia has a relationship with Hobsons Plc (Hobsons) and the URLs starting http://uea.hobsons.co.uk and https://app.hobsons.co.uk are hosted by Hobsons as part of this relationship. A list of the Cookies used by Hobsons for the processing of information on these pages can be found here: <http://www.hobsons.com/europe/cookies.php>. We do not employ any cookies to offer services or provide directed advertising. 

### **Security**

The University of East Anglia is committed to the security of our users' personal information and we have security procedures in place to protect against loss, misuse or alteration of personal information under the University's control.

### **Access to Data**

Should you wish to see any personal data relating to you that may have been collected via this website, please complete a ‘Subject Access Request' form available from [this page](https://portal.uea.ac.uk/information-services/strategy-planning-and-compliance/regulations-and-policies/information-regulations-and-policies/data-protection/requests-for-personal-information), the University's Information Policy and Compliance Manager, University of East Anglia, Norwich, NR4 7TJ (phone 01603 593523/2431, email [dataprotection@uea.ac.uk](mailto:dataprotection@uea.ac.uk)), or from University Reception. Please return the completed form to the University Information Policy and Compliance Manager.

## **UEA Disclaimer Statement**

The University of East Anglia makes all reasonable efforts to ensure that the information contained on the University's website is accurate at the time of creation and/or modification of the website. However, the University cannot guarantee the completeness or accuracy of information contained on the website and shall not be responsible for any errors, omissions, or inaccuracies and accepts no liability whatsoever for any loss or damage howsoever arising. The University reserves the right to make changes to or take down the web site or remove or alter any content at any time without notice.

Information on the website regarding courses is provided for information and guidance purposes only and does not constitute a contract and the University reserves the right to withdraw or to make alterations to courses and facilities if necessary. It is the responsibility of the user to check the accuracy of relevant information before entering into any commitment and the University accepts no liability for any loss or damage resulting directly or indirectly from inaccuracies in the information held on its website.

The University's web pages contain links to many external web sites which are not affiliated with the University of East Anglia. The University is not responsible for and has no control over these sites, and links to external sites should not be taken as a recommendation or endorsement of the external site's information, products or services. The University takes no responsibility for any loss or damage suffered as a result of using the linked web sites or as a result of using the information published on any of the pages of the linked web sites.

Whilst every effort is made to ensure that content is free from viruses and that that this website runs without any problems or interruptions, the University cannot accept any liability for damages resulting from virus infection and will not be liable for, nor take any responsibility for this website being temporarily unavailable due to technical or other reasons.

The University welcomes comments and suggestions on its website and would also welcome reports of any inaccuracies in the website - to do so, please e-mail [webmaster@uea.ac.uk](mailto:webmaster@uea.ac.uk).

## **UEA Copyright Statement**

Unless explicitly stated to the contrary, all rights, including copyright, in the content of these web pages (including, but not limited to, the University logo, and all text, layout, graphics, icons and artwork) are owned or controlled for these purposes by the University of East Anglia irrespective of whether a copyright symbol and/or statement is present.

In accessing the university's web pages, you agree that you may only download the content for your own personal non-commercial use. The material on these web pages should not be used, copied, stored or transmitted outside the University in any form or by any means, electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording or otherwise, without the prior written consent of the University or in accordance with the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988.

Permission is granted, however, for you to print for personal reference one hard copy only of any page held on the University's central web servers.

Further information in relation to the University's web site and this copyright notice can be obtained by emailing the University's Information Policy and Compliance Manager (phone: +44 (0)1603 593523/2431; email: [copyright@uea.ac.uk](mailto:copyright@uea.ac.uk)).
